Preliminary Inventory of the Czechoslovak Independent Publications Collection
Hoover Institution Archives
Czechoslovak independent publications collection,
1969-1990
2000C74
20 manuscript boxes (12 linear feet)
Hoover Institution on War, Revolution, and Peace Stanford, California 94305-6010
Serial issues, books, and pamphlets, published by underground and uncensored presses in Czechoslovakia, relating to political and cultural conditions in Czechoslovakia.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection is open for research.
Acquisition Information
Acquired in 2000.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog Socrates at http://library.stanford.edu/webcat. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in Socrates is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Scope and Content Note
Serial issues, books, and pamphlets, published by underground and uncensored presses in Czechoslovakia, relating to political and cultural conditions in Czechoslovakia.
Indexing Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the repository's online public access catalog.
Subjects
Underground literature--Czechoslovakia.; Censorship--Czechoslovakia.; Czechoslovakia--History--1968-1989.; Czechoslovakia--Civilization.; Czechoslovakia.
Container List
- Catalogue of Czech and Slovak samizdat books (Katalog knižní produkce českého a slovenského samizdatu), 1970-1989 (Box 1)
- Journals (Box 1)
  - Alternativa (Alternative)
    - 1988 December (Nr 1) (Box 1)
    - 1989 (Box 1)
      - April (Nr 2) (Box 1)
      - August (Nr 3) (Box 1)
  - Dialogy (Dialogues), 1978 (Nr 6-7) (Box 1)
  - Host (Guest) (Box 1)
    - 1985 May (Nr 1) (Box 1)
    - 1989 November (Nr 5) (Box 1)
  - Jazzstop (Box 1)
    - 1987 (Nr 1, Nr 2, Nr 3-4) (Box 1)
    - 1988 (Nr 5, Nr 6, Nr 7) (Box 1)
    - 1989 (Nr 8, Nr 9-10) (Box 1)
  - Kritický Sborník (Critical Review) (Box 2)
    - 1983 (Nr 4) (Box 2)
    - 1984 (Nr 2, Nr 4) (Box 2)
    - 1985 (Nr 3, Nr 4) (Box 2)
    - 1988 (Nr 4) (Box 2)
    - 1989 (Nr 1, Nr 2, Nr 3, Nr 4) (Box 2)
  - Lidové Noviny (People's News) (Box 3)
    - 1987 (Box 3)
      - September (Nr 0) (Box 3)
      - November (Nr 00) (Box 3)
    - 1988 (Box 3)
      - January (Nr 1) (Box 3)
      - March (Nr 3)
      - April (Nr 4) (Box 3)
      - May (Nr 5) (Box 3)
      - June (Nr 6) (Box 3)
      - July-August (Nr 7-8) (Box 3)
      - September (Nr 9) (Box 3)
      - October (Nr 10) (Box 3)
      - November (Nr 11) (Box 3)
      - December (Nr 12) (Box 3)
    - 1989 (Box 3)
      - January (Nr 1) (Box 3)
      - February (Nr 2) (Box 3)
      - March (Nr 3) (Box 3)
      - April (Nr 4) (Box 3)
      - May (Nr 5) (Box 3)
      - June (Nr 6) (Box 3)
      - July-August (Nr 7-8) (Box 3)
      - September (Nr 9) (Box 3)
      - October (Nr 10) (Box 3)
      - November (Nr 11) (Box 3)
      - December (Nr 12) (Box 3)
  - Revolver Revue (Revolver Review) – 1987 (Box 3)
    - Nr 7 (Box 3)
    - Nr 12 (Box 3)
  - Střední Evropa (Central Europe) (Box 3)
    - 1985 (Box 3)
      - Nr 1
      - Nr 2 (Box 3)
      - July (Nr 3) (Box 3)
      - November (Nr 4) (Box 4)
    - 1986 (Box 4)
      - July (Nr 5) (Box 4)
      - December (Nr 6) (Box 4)
    - 1987 (Box 4)
      - March (Nr 7) (Box 4)
      - July (Nr 8) (Box 4)
      - November (Nr 9) (Box 4)
    - 1988 (Box 4)
      - February (Nr 10) (Box 4)
      - July (Nr 11) (Box 4)
    - 1989 (Box 4)
      - January (Nr 12) (Box 4)
      - July (Nr 13)
- Monographs (Box 5)
  - Pevná pouta - moje náruč bilá (Milostne pisne srbskych a hercegovskych muslimu), Krameriova expedice, Prague (?), n.d.
    Anthology
  - Z pěstiček zatatých, Krameriova expedice, Prague, 1982. (Box 5)
    Anthology for Jan Skacel (60)
  - Černy, Václav, O povaze naši kultury, Petlice, Prague, 1975 (signed) (Box 5)
  - Cvetajeva, Marina, Myslete na mne na pražských mostech, Krameriova expedice, Prague, 1979 (Box 5)
  - Grögerová, Bohumila and Hiršal, Josef, Let let, Krameriova expedice, Prague, 1987 (signature and photograph included) (Box 5)
  - Gruša, Jiři, Modlitba pro Janinku, Krameriova expedice, Prague, 1987 (signature included?) (Box 5)
  - Halas, František, Říkám víc tichem než slovy, Česká expedice, Asyl, sv.5, Prague, 1981 (Box 5)
  - Hauková, Jiřina, Motýl a smrt, Kvart, Prague, 1983 (signature included) (Box 5)
  - Havel, Václav, Audience, Petlice, Prague, 1975 (signature included) (Box 5)
  - Hejda, Zbyněk, Básně, Petlice, Prague, 1979 (signature and photograph included) (Box 5)
  - Herbert, Zbigniew, Pan Cogito, Krameriova expedice, Prague, 1985 (Box 5)
  - Hiršal, Josef, Píseň mládí, Krameriova expedice, Prague, 1980 (signature included) (Box 5)
  - Hrabal, Bohumil, Kouzelná flétna (first edition), Cestou Poezie, Prague, 1989 (signature and frontispiece included) (Box 5)
  - Kalista, Zdeněk, Veliká noc, Česká expedice, Asyl sv. 13, Prague, 1987 (Box 5)
  - Klánský, Mojmír, Vyhnanství, Petlice, Prague, 1975 (signature included) (Box 5)
  - Klíma, Ivan, Má veselá jitra, Petlice, Prague, 1978 (signature included) (Box 6)
  - Kliment, Alexandr, Dona Juana, Petlice, Prague, 1976 (signature included) (Box 6)
  - Koestler, Arthur, Tma o polednách, Prague (?) (Box 6)
  - Kohout, Pavel, Pohled z okna, Krameriova expedice, Prague, 1980
  - Kolář, Jiří, Očitý svédek, Petlice, Prague, 1975 (signature included) (Box 6)
  - Kostohryz, Josef, Strmá nenaděj, Prague, 1987 (frontispiece included) (Box 6)
  - Lederer, Jiří, Lenka Procházková, Jan Palach, Prague, Edice Petlice sv., 1970-1988 (Box 6)
  - Pavliček, František (Box 6)
    - Dávno, dávno jiz tomu, Krameriova expedice, Prague, 1979 (signature and photograph included) (Box 6)
    - Chvála prostopášnosti, Krameriova expedice, Prague, 1980 (signature included) (Box 6)
    - Konec patriarchátu, Krameriova expedice, Prague, 1987 (signature and photograph included) (Box 6)
  - Pecka, Karel, Limita, Petlice, Prague, 1979 (signature included) (Box 6)
  - Sidon, Karol, Hry, Prague, 1974 (signature included) (Box 6)
  - Šimečka, Milan, Jr. (Box 6)
    - Dopisy o povaze skutečnosti, Prague, 1982 (Box 6)
    - Výpoved, Petlice, Prague, 1981 (Box 6)
  - Skácel, Jan, Malé recenze, Jazzova sekce (?), 1970's (?) (Box 6)
  - Škvorecký, Josef (Box 7)
    - Příbéh inženýra lidských duší, 4 vol., Krameriova expedice, Prague (?), n.d. (Box 7)
    - Scherzo Capriccioso (Antonín Dvořák), 2 vol., Krameriova expedice, Prague (?), n.d. (photograph included) (Box 7)
    - Prima sezóna, Krameriova expedice, Prague, 1978 (collages included) (Box 7)
  - Tatarka, Dominik, Sám proti noci, Krameriova expedice, Prague, 1990 (last book of the samizdat publishing house) (Box 7)
  - Uhde, Milan, Zubařovo pokušení, Petlice, Prague, 1976 (signature included) (Box 7)
  - Vaculík, Ludvík (Box 7)
    - Morčata, Petlice, Prague, 1973 (signature included) (Box 7)
    - Milí spolužáci! Petlice, Prague, 1981 (signature and photograph included) (Box 7)
  - Vladislav, Jan, Tajný čtenář, Petlice, Prague, 1975 (signature included) (Box 7)
  - Zahradníček, Jan, Ohrada času, Prague, 1985 (frontispiece included) (Box 7)
- Publications (Box 7)
  - Acta (Quarterly of the Documentation Centre for the Promotion of Independent Czechoslovak Literature, 1987, Nr 3, Nr 4)
  - Kabeš, Petr, Péší véc (Box 7)
  - Kostohryz, Josef, Melancholie (Box 7)
  - Solženicyn, Alexandr, Dopis představitelům sovětského svazu (Box 7)
- Miscellany (Box 7)
- Incremental Materials (Box 8)
  - Journals (Box 8)
    - Dialogy (Dialogues) (Box 8)
      - 1978 (Box 8)
        (Nr 6-7, II)
      - 1978 (Box 8)
        (Nr 8-9, II)
      - 1978 (Box 8)
        (Nr 10, II)
      - 1979 (Box 8)
        (Nr 1, III)
      - 1979 (Box 8)
        (Nr 2-3, III)
      - 1979 (Box 8)
        (Nr 4-5, III)
      - 1980 (Box 8)
        (Nr 1, IV)
      - 1980 (Box 8)
        (Nr 2-3, IV)
    - Horizont, 1984 (Box 8)
      (Nr 7)
    - Informace o církvi (About church) (Box 8)
      - 1985
        (Nr 9-12)
      - 1986 (Box 8)
        (Nr 1-4, 6-12)
      - 1987 (Box 9)
        (Nr 1-3, 10-12)
      - 1988 (Box 9)
        (Nr 1-12)
    - InformačníZpravodaj: ČeskoslovenskýHelsinský Výbor (Bulletin of the Czechoslovak Helsinki Committee), 1989 (Box 9)
      (Nr 1-5)
    - Kifu. Časopis Společnosti pro šiření informací v ČSSR, 1984 (Box 9)
      (Nr 5)
    - Křesťanské Obzory (Christian outlook) (Box 9)
      - 1988 (Box 9)
      - 1989 (Box 10)
      - 1990 (Box 10)
    - Listy. Časopis československé socialistické opozice, 1985 (Box 10)
      (Nr 1)
    - Mene Tekel Fares (Box 10)
      - 1981 (Box 10)
        (Nr 2-3)
      - 1982 (Box 10)
        (Nr 4)
    - O Divadle (About theatre) (Box 10)
      - 1986 July (Box 10)
      - 1987 February (Box 10)
      - 1987 November (Box 11)
      - 1988 October (Box 11)
      - 1989 October (Box 11)
    - Paraf. Paralelní Akta Filozofie (Parallel philosophical papers) (Box 11)
      - 1985 (Box 11)
        (Nr 1-2)
      - 1986 (Box 11)
        (Nr 3-5)
      - 1987 (Box 11)
        (Nr 6-7)
      - 1988 (Box 12)
        (Nr 8-9)
      - 1989 (Box 12)
        (Nr 10)
    - Potemník Revue, 1980 (Box 12)
      (Nr 3)
    - Prostor. Nezávislý časopis (Space: An independent journal) (Box 12)
      - 1983 (Box 12)
        (Nr 4-5)
      - 1987 (Box 12)
        (Nr 9-10)
      - 1988 (Box 12)
        (Nr 11)
      - 1989 (Box 12)
        (Nr 12)
    - Sport. Časopis pro kulturní a společenskou informaci, 1989 (Box 12)
      (Nr 1-4)
    - Studie. Křesťanská Akademie v Římě, 1980 (Box 12)
      (Nr 69)
    - Ze zásuvky i z bloku (Box 12)
      - 1985 May (Box 12)
      - 1986 (Box 12)
        - February (Box 12)
          (Nr 6)
        - (Nr 7) (Box 12)
        - (Nr 8) (Box 13)
        - November (Box 13)
          (Nr 9)
      - 1987 (Box 13)
        - February (Box 13)
        - March (Box 13)
        - June (Box 13)
        - September (Box 13)
          (Nr 13)
        - November (Box 13)
          (Nr 14)
      - 1988 (Box 13)
        - February (Box 13)
          (Nr 15)
        - April (Box 13)
          (Nr 16)
        - June (Box 13)
          (Nr 17)
        - September (Box 14)
          (Nr 18)
        - December (Box 14)
          (Nr 19)
      - 1989 (Box 14)
        - February (Box 14)
          (Nr 20)
        - April (Box 14)
          (Nr 21)
        - June (Box 14)
          (Nr 22)
        - October (Box 14)
          (Nr 23/24)
  - Monographs (Box 14)
    - Blatný, Ivan, Stará bydliště, n.d. (Box 14)
    - Čivrný, Lumír, Na dech, 1979 (Box 14)
      (signature included)
    - Daníček, Jiří, Dům z listí, KDM, 1980 (Box 14)
    - Deml, Jakub, Moji přatelé, n.d. (Box 14)
    - Dvořák, Ladislav (Box 14)
      - Dílo I, verše, Praha, 1984 (Box 14)
      - Dílo II, prózy, Praha, 1984 (Box 14)
      - Dílo III, verže a prózy pro děti, Praha, 1984 (Box 15)
      - Šavle meče. Prózy z padesátých let, Praha, 1983 (Box 15)
    - Fikar, Ladislav, Kámen na hrob. Verše z let 1970-1972, Praha, 1979 (Box 15)
    - Gruša, Jiří (Box 15)
      - D ámský gambit aneb Il Ritorno d'Ulisse in Patria. Dramma in Musica, opravené vydání, 1972 (Box 15)
      - Modlitba k Janince, Praha, 1969-1973 (Box 15)
    - Havel, Václav (Box 15)
      - Asanace. Hra o pěti jednáních, 1987 (Box 15)
      - Moc bezmocných, 1978 (Box 15)
      - Dopisy Olze, Praha, 1983 (Box 15)
    - Heidegger, Martin, Gesamtausgabe. 1. Abt.: Veroeffentlichte Schriften 1914-1970, Band 2: Sein und Zeit, 1977 (Box 15)
      (Předklad)
    - Hejda, Zbyněk, Blízkosti smrti, Kde domov můj, 1978 (Box 15)
    - Hrabal, Bohumil (Box 15)
      - Texty, 1952; 1970 (Box 15)
      - Městečko kde se zastavil čas, 1973 (Box 15)
    - Kantůrková, Eva, Pán věže, 1979 (Box 16)
    - Klíma, Ivan, Malomocní, 1972 (Box 16)
    - Kliment, Alexandr, Nuda v Čechách, 1976 (Box 16)
    - Kníže, Roman, Kabát můj větrný, KDM, 1979 (Box 16)
    - Kohout, Pavel, Bílá kniha, n.d. (Box 16)
    - Landovský, Pavel (Box 16)
      - Hry, 1978 (Box 16)
      - Sanitární noc. Divadelní podivaná o dvou íástech, zaěítku, přestívce a konci, 1976 (Box 16)
    - Muehlen, Heribert, Zácvik do Křesťanství, Matthias-Gruenewald-Verlag, 1978 (Box 16)
    - Orwell, George, Farma zvířat, 1946 (Box 16)
    - Pátek, Miloslav, Konfident. Zamišlení nad životem Karla Sabiny, 1977 (Box 16)
    - Pavlát, Leo, Osm světel, n.d. (Box 16)
    - Pavlíček, František, Dávno, dávno již tomu. Zpráva o pohřbívání v Čechách, 1979 (Box 16)
    - Petr, Antonín, Umřu, Kde domov můj, 1978 (Box 16)
    - Seifert, Jaroslav, Všecky krásy světa. Příběhy a vzpomínky, n.d. (Box 17)
    - Serie Trefulka, Chvála bláznovství, 1979 (Box 17)
    - Sidon, Karol (Box 17)
      - Evangelium podle Josefa Flavta, 1969-1970 (Box 17)
      - Starý příběh, 1977 (Box 17)
    - Šiktanc, Karel (Box 17)
      - Pro pět ran blázna krále, 1978 (Box 17)
      - Tanec smrti aneb ještě pámbu neumřel, 1974-1975 (Box 17)
    - Šípková, Růžena, Má tajemství, n.d. (Box 17)
    - Skácel, Jan, Talisman, tratidla, nepatrné requiem, n.d. (Box 17)
    - Škutina, Vladimír, Pražské jaro 1968 s Janem Werichem, n.d. (Box 17)
    - ŠorŠová, Zdeňka, Žití mého proude sladký..., 1959-1962 (Box 17)
    - Trefulka, Jan, O blaáznech jen dobré, 1973 (Box 17)
    - Turnovský, Evžen, Zápis (I.), 1983 (Box 17)
    - Uhde, Milan, Pán plamínků, 1977 (Box 17)
    - Vaculík, Ludvík, České snář, 1981 (Box 17)
    - Von le Fort, Gertrud, Hymny na církev, Franz Ehrenwirth Verlag, 1970 (Box 18)
    - Zahradníček, Jan, Dům strach (Box 18)
  - Publications of Palach Press Limited (Box 18)
    - Bulletin, 1977 (Box 18)
      (Nr 5-8)
    - Informace o Chartě 77, 1986 (Box 18)
      (Nr 3-6, 8-9)
    - Sdělení Výbor na obranu nespravedlivě stíhaných (Vons) (Box 18)
      - 1978 (Box 18)
        (Nr 1-63)
      - 1979 (Box 18)
        (Nr 64-167)
      - 1980 (Box 18)
        (Nr 168-226)
      - 1981 (Box 18)
        (Nr 230-349) with gaps
      - (Nr 591) (Box 18)
    - Summary of available documents (Box 18)
      - 1977 (Box 18)
        (Nr 7-8)
      - 1978 (Box 18)
    - Uncensored Czechoslovakia: Palach Press Infoch Summary of Information on Charter 77 (Box 19)
      - 1988 (Box 19)
        (Nr 19-22)
      - 1989 (Box 19)
    - Miscellany (Box 19)
      - Announcements, press releases, price lists, 1982-1990 (Box 19)
      - Book review, 1980 (Box 19)
      - Judgment actions, 1969-1984 (Box 19)
      - Letters, minutes, reports, etc. issued by both the dissident community and the Czechoslovak government, 1979-1985 (Box 19)
      - Political essays, 1979-1985 (Box 19)
      - Political essays, 1979-1985 (Box 20)